JUSTIN NALDZIN

DATA ENGINEER -

215 - 307 - 6449



justinnaldzin@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/justinnaldzin



justinnaldzin.github.io



Philadelphia, Pennsylvania



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A driven data engineer experienced in identifying deficiencies, implementing corrective solutions to reduce production impact and supporting systems and applications critical to operational workflow. Areas of focus include operational intelligence, cloud infrastructure monitoring and alerting, business intelligence, data visualization and analytics, scripting and automation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA ENGINEER

Penn Medicine | Philadelphia | November 2016 - Present

The Data Analytics Center is responsible for ensuring 100's of terabytes of Penn Medicine's healthcare data reaches partner organizations, internal vendor applications, local/state/federal government institutions, and research collaborators.

- · Created a portable, reproducible, and fully automated application designed to benchmark various database platforms and big data technologies
- Statistical analysis on medical claims using Spark to understand patient demographics
- Work on Hadoop platform housing access logs containing 27 billion rows
- · Geocoding of patients, providers, and facilities using Google Maps API to measure distances understand patients' behaviors

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Comcast | Philadelphia | October 2015 - November 2016

A member of a DevOps team responsible for the operations and infrastructure of the Xfinity On Demand ingest, encoding/packaging, quality control and publishing workflows delivering QAM and IP video to XfinityTV.com, Xfinity.com, mobile iOS/Android apps and various connected devices in the home.

- Develop a real-time network infrastructure monitoring and alerting system
- Produce complex, recurring and ad-hoc reports and dashboards with the purpose of measuring progress towards goals, performance against objectives, as well as identifying improvement opportunities
- Collaborate with the Architecture team on continuous integration deployments to understand changes and assess production impact
- Extract and analyze data from APIs and translate data-driven insight into decisions that improve customer experience
- Develop technical documentation for operations team and deliver presentations on operational matters to peers and executives

SKILLS

Python
SQL
Splunk
Business Intelligence / Visualization
Spark
Hadoop
Linux
Automation
Video Transcoding

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE / COMPUTER SCIENCE WEST CHESTER UNIVERSITY. West Chester, PA | 1998-2002

JUSTIN NALDZIN

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

VIDEO & DATA ANALYTICS LEAD

Comcast | Philadelphia | March 2011 - October 2015

Responsible for data metrics and reporting of the entire Video Operations value chain.

- Develop scripts and utilities to automate data collection from APIs and databases
- Produce time-series charts and dashboards for ingest volume, encoding efficiency, and track storage usage and capacity
- Identify patterns and trends in data and implement corrective solutions to maximize efficiency and improve user experience
- Alert on server task failures within publishing workflow
- Ensure accuracy and optimize performance of data stores
- Serve as a reporting liaison between the content team, data integration team, product owners, and senior management to communicate technical findings

SENIOR VIDEO SPECIALIST

Comcast Interactive Media | Philadelphia | September 2006 - March 2011

Extensive knowledge of analog and digital video transcoding technologies using SD/HD video formats, NTSC standards and CableLabs specifications.

- Adaptive bitrate streaming: Apple HLS, Adobe HDS, Microsoft Smooth Streaming
- Streaming media protocols: HTTP, RTMPE
- Video/audio codecs and compression: H.264, MPEG, VP6, MP3, AC-3, AAC
- Container formats: FLV, MOV, AVI, 3GP, MPEG-2 TS
- Networking technologies: TCP/IP, DNS, AFP, SMB

REFERENCES



SCOTT MCGILL
SENIOR MANAGER
Comcast
Scott McGill@comcast.com



GREG SOKOLOFF

DIRECTOR

Comcast

Gregory Sokoloff@comcast.com

EXPERTISE

SCRIPTING & DEVELOPMENT LANGUAGES:

 Python (Pandas, NumPy), Scala, Ruby, PHP, bash, HTML, JavaScript, CSS

DATA SCIENCE:

• Spark SQL, Hadoop, Hive, Cassandra

DATA STORES:

Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, MariaDB, HANA

OPERATING SYSTEMS:

 Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, macOS, Windows

VIRTUALIZATION TECHNOLOGIES:

• OpenStack, VirtualBox, VMware

CONFIGURATION MANAGEMENT:

• Vagrant, Docker, Puppet

MONITORING & ALERTING:

• Nagios, Zabbix

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE:

• Splunk, Tableau, Lumira

AGILE PROJECT TRACKING:

• Jira, Rally

VERSION CONTROL AND INTEGRATION TOOLS:

· Git, GitHub, Jenkins

OTHER RELEVANT KNOWLEDGE:

 Splunk Certified Knowledge Manager, Elemental, Aspera, CDN, NetApp, HDFS, CableLabs, XML, JSON, RESTful Web Services

SOCIAL MEDIA







